# Kevin Reid

Oshawa, ON| (289)688-8896 | kevinnivek@me.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://github.com/Vinyldude8896">www.linkedin.com/in/kevinreidkr</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Vinyldude8896">https://github.com/Vinyldude8896</a> Portfolio: <a href="https://vinyldude8896.github.io/portfolio\_react">https://vinyldude8896.github.io/portfolio\_react</a>

## Summary

Full stack developer experienced in technical support, customer experience and logistics. Applied data-driven process improvement in my logistics and customer experience roles. My technical support experience has benefited me in logistics to problem solve and come up with possible solutions. This experience has also benefited me greatly during my training as a Web developer, as being a good problem solver is crucial. I am excited to take the customer experience skills, technical support skills, and logistics information and build clean, efficient, and best customer-experience web applications.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, Node.js, Hanndlebars.js, Chart.js, React.js

Applications: Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench, Insomnia

**Tools:** Git, Web API, Third-Party API, RESTful API, Sequelize, Mongoose, Webpack

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, IndexedDB, GraphQL | Platforms: Heroku

**Architecture:** Model-View-Controller, Object-Relational-Mapping, Test Driven Deployment

## **Projects**

### Tech Blog

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/Vinyldude8896/The-Tech-Blog">https://github.com/Vinyldude8896/The-Tech-Blog</a> **Deployed Project:** <a href="https://immense-cliffs-94479.herokuapp.com">https://immense-cliffs-94479.herokuapp.com</a>

- This deployed app is a blog style website that provides a secure signup and login for the user. Users can view posts and comments from other users, or create their own posts, edit or delete posts, add comments on other users' posts and delete those comments they made.
- Uses: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, Express.js, Handlebars.js

#### **Employee Tracker**

GitHub: https://github.com/Vinyldude8896/Employee-Tracker

Walkthrough: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ziSfSc\_Dury25gX0I-vqKOJPjDzP50Ao/view

- This is a command line input application that handles the CRUD(Create Read Update and Delete) operations for a company's department, employees and roles database tables. This app uses the Inquirer package to prompt the user for input.
- Uses: JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL

#### iBetter

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/Vinyldude8896/iBetter">https://github.com/Vinyldude8896/iBetter</a> **Deployed Project:** <a href="https://ibetter.herokuapp.com/">https://ibetter.herokuapp.com/</a>

- This is a habit tracker app, that has a secure login. You are able to add, edit or create habits. Track your progress using an interactive table and see your monthly progress in the bar chart.
- Uses: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, bcrypt, Chart.js, sequelize and MySQL

## Experience

## Process Assistant/Assistant Manager - November 2021 - Present

Amazon Logistics Whitby, ON

Working with various teams to ensure the highest level of delivery success

- Increased delivery success rate, decreased parcels not on van, decreased customer escalations over a significant period by implementing new data sources and reporting tools, and by communicating this data to our teams.
- Using various logistic tracking, reporting and communication tools and software to track progress of station packages, drivers on the road, and failed delivery attempts.

## Delivery Station Liaison - May 2021-November 2021

Amazon Logistics Whitby, ON

Working with third-party vendors and station staff to resolve customer escalations and missed deliveries

- Created a new data driven tool to help our team be more successful in tracking escalations, common delivery failed attempts, and common issues.
- Analyzed and collected data to improve processes and metrics; created tools to improve workflow within the team.
- Identified recurring delivery issues and worked towards resolutions that would impact future delivery success.

## Owner/Operator - eBay Store

Penkey Collectibles 2011 - 2021

Online retail/resale store specializing in video game and memorabilia

- Very strong focus on customer service and satisfaction.
- Purchasing, inventory, shipping and receiving of all products.

## **Education**

### **Full Stack Web Development - Certificate**

University of Toronto - April 2022 - October 2022

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and the MERN Stack.

#### **Object Oriented Programming**

Advanced Business Technologies - 1998-2000 Java, PowerBuilder, Visual Basic